We've seen that CNNs achieve state-of-the-art and
我们看到 CNN 在对象分类任务方面
sometimes superhuman performance in object classification tasks.
取得了一些非常先进甚至超人一般的效果
We've explored some techniques for building CNN architectures,
我们学习了一些构建 CNN 架构的技巧
and we've gotten some good performance on toy datasets.
并且在示例数据集中获得了很好的效果
But at the end of the day,
但是最终
we don't really have a strong understanding of how
我们并不能完全明白
these CNNs discover patterns in raw image pixels.
这些 CNN 是如何从原始图片像素中发现规律的
If you've already taken the time to train your own CNNs,
如果你已经花时间训练自己的 CNN
you've noticed that some architectures work while some just don't.
就会发现有些架构能正常运转 有些则不行
And if it's not clear to you why that's the case,
如果你不知道为何是这种情形
it's probably not truly clear to the experts either.
那么可能专业人士也不清楚
Earlier in this lesson,
在这节课的早些时间
I mentioned visualizing the activation maps and convolutional layers
我提到通过可视化激活映射和卷积层
as one technique for digging deeper into understanding how a CNN is working.
深入了解 CNN 的工作原理
There are many implementations of this online.
网上有很多这种实现方法
This is one of them,
这是其中一种实现
and as you can see,
可以看出
it's designed to pass your webcam's video through a trained CNN in real time.
该实现会实时地将你的摄像头录制的视频传入训练过的 CNN
If you'd like to play around with this,
如果你想研究下该实现
you're encouraged to check out the links below.
请点击下方的链接
Another technique designed for understanding CNNs involves taking the filters from
另一种用来理解 CNN 的技巧是
our convolutional layers and constructing images that maximize their activations.
从卷积层中获取过滤器并构建最大化这些过滤器激活的图片
You can start with an image containing random noise and then gradually amend the pixels,
你可以首先使用包含随机噪音的图片 然后逐步修复像素
and each step changing them to values that make the filter more highly activated.
每一步都将像素更改为使过滤器更加激活的值
When you do this, you'll notice that the first three layers are pretty general.
在此过程中 你会发现前三个层级很普通
The first layer might include color or edge detectors,
第一个层级可能包含颜色或边缘检测器
where the second layer detects circles or stripes.
第二个层级负责检测圆圈或条纹
The filters later in the network are activated by much more complicated patterns.
网络中后续的过滤器由更复杂的规律激活
Researchers at Google got creative with this.
Google 的研究人员在此基础上加以创新
They designed a technique called deep dreams
他们设计了一种叫做 Deep Dreams 的技巧
where they replace the starting image with a picture.
他们将起始图片替换成一张照片
Say we have a picture of a tree,
例如这张大树的照片
but you can use a picture of anything here.
当然你可以使用任何照片
Then, you could investigate one of the more interesting filters,
然后可以研究更加有趣的过滤器
maybe one that looks like it's used for detecting a building.
例如用来检测建筑物的过滤器
When you follow the same technique where the only thing
采用相同的技巧
you've changed is the starting array of pixels,
唯一变化的是起始像素数组
you end up creating an image that looks like some sort of tree or building hybrid.
最终创建的图片看起来像某种大树或建筑物混合图片
If you'd like to code this yourself in Keras,
如果你想自己在 Keras 中编写此技巧的代码
you're encouraged to pursue this in the links below.
建议你点击下方的链接
There are many other techniques for visualizing what a CNN learns.
还有很多其他技巧可以用来可视化 CNN 学到的规律
We've only scratched the surface with this,
我们只是提到了一些皮毛知识
but you're definitely encouraged to explore more in this area.
强烈建议你深入探索这一领域
The idea is that if we can understand more of what a CNN learns,
如果我们能进一步理解 CNN 所学的规律
we can help it to perform even better.
就可以帮助它提高效果